DANIEL HOPPER

Contact Information

<u>E-mail</u>: djhopper@uwaterloo.ca <u>Website</u>: danielhopper.github.io

Phone: (647) 880-9655

Home Address

6354 Snowflake Lane Mississauga, ON L5N 6G9

(905) 824-8745

OBJECTIVE

With an eager mindset and a true passion for the craft, I wish to apply both the technical and theoretical knowledge of Computer Science that I have gained from my first 3 terms at UW, along with my creative drive/ability, to a position where I can create, learn, and thrive in the surrounding culture.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Successfully completed courses building proficiency in Racket and C

Familiar with Linux (Ubuntu), working knowledge of using bash and writing scripts

Actively learning C++ in class, and HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript out of class Knowledge of Java, started in highschool and developed through side projects

Experience with small group version control using Git bash

Knowledge and active use of Abstract Data Types and Algorithms

ASSIGNMENTS AND PROJECTS

CS135: Designing Function Programs - Polyomino Assignment (Racket)

Developed, using knowledge of graphs, a 'neighbours' function used in an algorithm to solve a puzzle of fitting various sized polyominoes onto a fixed grid.

hackWaterloo hackathon project: waterLOOKup (Java)

Developed from scratch a simple application that uses the UW API to find the closest possible room on campus that is free for a given amount of time. Use of GPS location, plans to extend to cross-platform mobile HTML5 web app.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UW Athletics, Waterloo, ON

Front Desk

Sept. 2013 - Jan. 2014

Managed front desk operations at UW athletic facilities. Using equipment rental/booking management software, working under busy time sensitive scenarios, customer service.

Global Marketing Inc., Mississauga, ON

Sales Representative

July 2012 - Sept. 2012

Door-to-door promotion and sales of various newspaper subscriptions. Interacted with 50+ people per day, communication and sales skills, individual work, responsibilty for own sales and customers.

EDUCATION

2A Honours Computer Science, Management Studies Minor

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

Student ID: 20524307

AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

University of Waterloo

President's Scholarship (90+ admission average), May 2013

Our Lady of Mount Carmel Secondary School

Graduating Class Salutatorian, June 2013

Dramatic Arts Academic Achievement/Performance Award, June 2013

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

Photography

Member of the UW Photo Club since Sept. 2013, work available on 500px.

Dramatic Arts

Involved in theatre community in and out of school, most recent performance in June 2013

Student Council

Grade representative in Student Council from 2011-2013, and Social Convenor in senior year. Responsible for event planning, promotion, and MC'ing large events for the entire school.